

Status: Data Scientist @ Argus Media Field: Software Engineering, Data Science Techs: R, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Python Didcot, UK

Summary

Data Scientist and R Shiny Developer with strong experience in R development. Skilled in creating interactive data visualizations and applications. A quick learner with a good understanding of data analysis, statistical methods, and machine learning. Focused on delivering practical solutions and continuously improving my skills. Enjoy working with data and keeping up with new tools and techniques in the field.

Experience

Data Scientist - Argus Media

Jan 2022 - Present

- * Successfully delivered a GBP250,000 web-based solution for Kuwait Petroleum International (KPI), a major European transport fuel supplier
- * Building production ready Shiny dashboards for commodity traders using golem framework
- * Building custom Shiny inputs using JavaScript to enhance user experience
- * Manage user permission and data storage with MySQL and AWS S3
- * Contributing to the data preparation pipeline that feeds into the models forecasting commodity prices and distribution

Senior Data Science Specialist - Ricardo Energy & Environment

Jan 2020 - Jan 2022

- * Building R Shiny applications integrated with SQL database for data checking and ratification
- * Building bespoke R packages to simplify the process of data analysis
- * Using regression and tree based statistical models to predict air quality trends
- * Building Python CLI tool to scrape and compare data from XML files

Data Science Specialist - Ricardo Energy & Environment

Apr 2017 - Jan 2020

- * Mentoring staff on doing data analysis in R
- * Dynamic reporting, data visualisation and building tools for analysing air quality data

Education

Ph.D. - University of Edinburgh, UK

2017

- * Understanding the spatial-temporal variability of urban air pollution
- * Dispersion and statistical modelling of urban air pollution
- * Conducting air quality measurements using stationary and portable air quality monitors.

BSc (1st Class) - University of Edinburgh, UK

2013

* Environmental and Sustainable Chemistry

BSc - South China University of Technology, China

2013

* Applied Chemistry

Teaching Experience

Teaching assistant - Ricardo

2019

* Teaching assistant at Ricardo openair and R data analysis training course

- $\ ^*$ Second Year Physical Chemistry Lab Demonstrator
- $\ ^*$ Second Year Environmental Chemistry Lab Demonstrator